Blaze Smith

715-573-4995

blazewaynesmith@gmail.com
Milwaukee, WI 53202

SUMMARY

High-performing **corporate experience** with over **three** years of delivering successful improvements for business operations, profitability and team development. Resourceful manager and compliance specialist to thrive in fast-paced and changing environments. Dedicated to sustaining operational accuracy and delivering results for optimal profitability.

SKILLS

- Decision Making
- Quality Assurance
- Originality and Creativity
- Focus and Follow-Through
- Team Leadership

- Customer Service Management
- Training Management
- Product Transportation
- Desktops, Laptops and Mobile Devices
- Multitasking and Prioritization

EXPERIENCE

Food Expeditor, Valet, Busser

Milwaukee, WI

Mo's A Place for Steaks/ Sep 2021 to Present

- Played a key role in bolstering high-end dining experience by optimizing resources allocation.
- Maintained speed of service for food orders while minimizing errors and complaints.
- Assisted preparation of food plates, overseeing quality and appearance.
- Delivered guest vehicles smoothly and met diverse needs of valet customers.
- Maintained cleanliness of work sites, parking spaces and guest services stations.
- Kept close eye on customers to quickly spot leaving guests and clear tables for future patrons.
- Worked quickly, communicated with other staff and always looked for better ways of completing tasks to improve productivity and keep tables ready for incoming guests.

Operations Manager

New Berlin, WI

FedEx Smartpost/ Jul 2021 to Sep 2021

- Directed day-to-day operations by spearheading implementation of short-term and long-term strategies to achieve business plan and profitability goals.
- Conducted performance reviews providing coaching and feedback to benefit both company and employee.
- Managed company operations with responsibility for profit and loss,

- scheduling, training and inventory control.
- Implemented policies and standard operating procedures and managed quality, customer service and logistics.
- Delivered positive customer experiences by implementing effective quality assurance practices.
- Collaborated with staff to maximize customer satisfaction, streamline procedures and improve bottom-line profitability.
- Planned daily operational strategies, including delivery routing, team workflows and promotional initiatives.
- Maintained safety and emergency readiness among personnel by disseminating information on and monitoring compliance with regulatory and organizational policies.

Operations Admin

Wausau, WI

FedEx Ground/ Oct 2019 to Jul 2021

- Performed dock duties to assist the outbound sorts such as scanning VSA packages, repackaging damaged goods, giving support to Van/Linehaul Drivers.
- Wrote email messages, memos and business letters for management and proofread all documentation to provide error-free correspondence.
- Responsible for the moving of trailers in a switcher that requires a switching certification.
- Worked professionally to handle all customer and vendor requirements.
- Answered phone calls and asked appropriate questions to determine which department or staff member could be of service.
- Attended meetings and took meticulous notes to disseminate to all participants.
- On dock training performed with multiple new employees at a time during peak season.

Package Handler

Wausau, WI

FedEx Ground/ May 2018 to Oct 2019

- Assisted in loading/unloading outbound trailers with prepared packages.
- Loaded completed orders on pallets according to delivery numbers.
- Operated pallet jacks to move, pick up or store products.
- Protected company inventory by maintaining and organizing storage areas.

- Braced, padded and supported shipments to prevent shifting and damage.
- Palletized boxes to streamline movement and shipment.
- Resolved conveyor system issues by clearing jams and blockages.
- Alerted team of shortages or damaged goods identified when unloading trucks.
- Handled hazardous material to ensure safety of contents.
- Inspected outgoing shipments to maintain quality assurance standards.
- Mentored new employees on warehouse procedures and tasks resulting in quick job acclimation.

<u>Housekeeper</u>

Wausau, WI

Hampton Inn By Hilton/ Aug 2017 to May 2018

- Vacuumed floors and dusted furniture to maintain organized, professional appearance at all times.
- Interacted pleasantly with clients and guests when performing daily duties.
- Moved beds, sofas and small furniture to wipe down baseboards and remove dust and dirt from hard-to-reach areas.
- Removed finger marks and smudges from doors, frames and glass partitions to enhance shine.
- Employed deep-cleaning techniques for areas in need of additional sanitation.
- Emptied wastebaskets and disposed of all soiled linen in guest rooms to reduce spread of germs and enhance freshness.
- Laundered sheets and removed stains to restore linens to pristine condition.
- Created checklists for daily stocking of housekeeping carts to improve inventory management and prevent unnecessary trips to stockroom.
- Coordinated delivery of extra room furniture, bedding, linen and towels to meet guests needs.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

High School Diploma

Wittenberg-Birnamwood High School: May 2018

Wittenberg, WI

Associate Degree: Web Design

Northcentral Technical College: Expected Spring 2023

Wausau, WI

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Programming: HTML, CSS, C#, JavaScript, MySQL
- FedEx Power Industrial Truck/Switcher Certified
- FedEx Tugger Certified

HOBBIES

- Weight Training
- Skiing
- Mountain Biking
- Designing and Creating Clothing Shopify eCommerce